准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
他们要拨号了
They're preparing to dial the Gate.
快好了
Yeah, almost finished.
我知道 我很不会打包
I know, I'm terrible at packing.
我永远不知道该带多少东西
I never know how much to bring.
我们只是去过一个晚上
We are only going overnight.
我确定你带的足够了
I'm sure you have enough.
你觉得够了 但是...
Well, you'd think so, but...
你看上去很紧张
You seem nervous.
哦 不 我没有
Oh, no, I'm fine.
也许有一点点
Well, maybe a little.
到外星球对我来说还有点新奇
Going off-world
is still kind of new to me.
到完全不同的一个星系
还要接触新的文明...
Whole other galaxy
and meeting new civilizations...
我的族人非常的好客
他们很急切地想见到你
My people are very welcoming
and they're eager to meet you.
我也很像见到他们
学习学习他们的文化和历史
Well, I'm eager to meet them, too, learn about their culture
and their history.
他们会很欣赏你这样的态度的
A gesture for which
they will be most grateful.
只是...
It's just...
我知道他们很喜欢Carson
I know they were very fond of Carson.
我只希望他们觉得
我能有他一半好就够了
I only hope to make
half the impression he did.
这些是什么?
What are those?
棒棒糖
Oh, lollipops.
给小孩子吃的
For the kids.
这样检查可以轻松一点
Makes the check-ups go easier.
你肯定会给他们留下很好的印象的
You will make a wonderful impression.
喔 看看你
Look at you.
有约会吗?
Got a date?
好啦
Please.
如果有需要 就连系我们
You will contact us if you need us?
我们不会有事的
Oh, we'll be fine.
你们好好玩
You kids have fun.
你会爱死Athosian人的
You're gonna love the Athosians.
我要体验我的第一个Tandul盛宴
I'm going to experience
my first tandul feast.
那个很不错的 但是你得当心...
Oh, those are good, but watch out for the...
你们叫那个什么来这?
- What do you call it?
Roos酒
- Roos wine.
Roos wine.
味道很好 但是后劲很强
Tasty stuff, but a hell of a kick.
我们真的要走了
We really should be going.
好好玩 孩子们
Have fun, kids.
穿过森林就是定居点了
- The settlement is through the woods.
你带路
- Lead the way.
路程有点长 我来帮你拿这些吧
It is some distance.
Let me help you with those.
不用 没关系的
Oh no, no, it's okay.
是我自己白痴 打了这么多东西
I'm the idiot who over-packed.
我就应该自己拿
I should be the idiot carrying them.
看来Sheppard对于今晚的
So Sheppard was right, huh?
激情约会说得没错啊?
About that hot date tonight?
我真没想到会有这么远
I didn't think it would be this far.
这里一直是这么安静吗?
Is it always this quiet?
出事了
Something is wrong.
有人吗?
Hello?
有人吗!
Hello!
有人在吗?
Is anybody here?
大家都到哪去了?
Where is everyone?
我不知道 但是他们不是自愿离开的
I do not know, but they did not leave
of their own accord.
你是说他们被攻击了?
Are you saying they were attacked?
或者是被洗劫了
Or culled.
Stargate Atlantis
《星际之门：亚特兰提斯》
第四季 第7集
Season 4 Episode 07
Missing (v. 1.01)
我以为Wraith不知道这个星球
I thought the Wraith
didn't know about this planet.
我也是这么想的
That was my understanding as well.
那么 他们怎么会...
Well then, how could they just...
怎么了?
What is it?
你认识他们?
You know them?
我们必须离开
We must leave.
好的 到这里来
Over here.
放武器的地方太远了
The weapons cache is too far.
什么?
- What?
我们最好逃到星门那边去
- Better to make a run for the gate.
你在找什么?
What are you looking for?
你有带武器吗?
Did you bring a weapon?
没有 只有医疗用品
No, it's just medical supplies.
你没有带武器?
Don't you have a weapon?
只有一把刀
Just a knife.
我本来是来看望我的人民的
I was coming to visit my people.
我没想到我会需要枪
I did not believe I would need a gun.
那些是什么人?
- Who are those men?
Bola kai
- Bola Kai.
你认识他们?
- You know them?
我知道他们
- I know of them.
他们脸上的标记是他们部落特有的
The markings on their faces
are distinctive to their tribe,
但是我从没和他们交过锋...
but I have never
crossed paths with them...
直到现在
Until now.
他们危险吗?
Are they dangerous?
远远超过那个等级
Beyond dangerous.
我们走
Let's go.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我扭到了脚踝
I twisted my ankle.
我们得继续走
We have to keep moving.
等一下
Just hang on a sec.
骨折了吗?
Is it broken?
没有 我不觉得
No, I don't think so.
可能只是扭伤
It's probably just sprained.
把包丢在这 它太重了
Leave the bag. It's too heavy.
上帝 现在我们怎么办
Oh, God, what do we do?
要返回放武器的地方太危险了
It is too risky to return
to the weapons cache.
什么地方?
What weapons cache?
我们给了我的族人一些枪
以让他们自卫
We gave my people guns to protect themselves
in the event they were raided.
你...你为什么觉得
那些枪还会在那?
What makes you think
that the guns would still there?
那些人不会首先就把他们偷走吗?
Wouldn't that be the first thing
those guys would steal?
如果Bola kai偷了枪
他们就会用的
If the Bola Kai stole them,
they would be using them.
但是放武器的地方太远了
尤其是在你这种情况下
But the weapons cache is too far, especially in your condition,
而且我们不知道
还有多少Bola kai在这
and we have no idea how many
more Bola Kai are out there.
我们最好的选择
是自己干掉这些守卫
Our best option is to take out
these guards by ourselves.
干掉他们? 你在说什么啊?
Take them out?
What are you talking about?
我们怎么干掉他们?
How are we going to do that?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
嘿 我和你不一样
Hey, listen,
I am not like you.
我完全不会战斗
I don't know anything about fighting.
按我说的做就好了
Just do what I say.
相信我 我也想 但是...
I want to, believe me, but I...
我不认为我可以
I don't think I can.
你一定不能这么想
You must think otherwise.
我们首先得创造一个...
What we first need to do is create a...
他们走了
They're gone.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道你对这种事没有准备
I know this is something
for which you are unprepared.
我知道我应该有准备的
I should be prepared, I know.
不幸的是 我恐怕
事情暂时只会变得更糟
Unfortunately, I'm afraid things may
get worse before they get better.
那些守卫会向其他人发出警示
他们会追捕我们
Those guards will alert and they will hunt us.
the others to our situation,
我们躲得时间越长
生存的机率就越大
The longer we avoid capture,
the better our chances.
他们会继续把守星门 但是时间一长
They will continue
to guard the Gate, yes,
Atlantis会发现我们迟到了
然后派出救援队
but in time,
Atlantis will realize we are late,
and they will send a rescue team.
但是我们应该是明天才回去的
But we're not due back till tomorrow.
所以在那之前我们必须逃避捕捉
It is therefore critical that
we elude capture until then.
你的伤要怎么处理?
What do you need to help your injury?
我应该包扎一下
但是绷带在医疗包里
Well, I should probably wrap it, but the ace bandages
are in the medical kit.
那包在到武器库的路上
The kit is on the way
to the weapons cache.
希望它还在我们放....
Hopefully, it'll still be where we...
那是什么?
What is that?
他们在召集其他人了
They are summoning the others, gathering them.
追捕已经开始了
The hunt is beginning.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
你动作得快一点
- You must move quickly.
我会的
- I will.
布洛芬(Ibuprofen)
Ibuprofen.
可以缓解疼痛和消肿
- Helps with the pain and swelling.
没错 McKay博士常用这个药
- Yes. Dr. Mckay uses them frequently,
还有抗组织胺药 抗酸药 晕车药...
along with antihistamines, antacids, motion-sickness pills...
你忘了说我刚开给他的
治疗不安跟综合症状药
You forgot the prescription I just
wrote him for restless leg syndrome.
我一直是一个很软弱的人
I've always been a wimp.
很不能忍受疼痛
I've got a low threshold for pain.
人们总是低估他们能忍受的不适
People often underestimate they are capable of enduring.
the level of discomfort
小时候 我和几个同伴一起
被送到森林里独自呆了10天
When I was a child, several of us were
sent into the woods for 10 days alone.
独自呆了10天?
10 days alone?
这是我们民族的一种考验仪式
It is a rite of passage among my people.
没有食物 也没有水
No food, no water.
被迫自己求生
Forced to survive on our own.
我们都不相信我们可以坚持
但是我们都做到了
None of us believed we could endure it,
but all of us did.
我去过一个夏令营
I went to summer camp.
那里还有其他的小孩
There were other kids.
我们住在小木屋里
We had cabins.
还有床睡
With beds.
有电有水
And electricity, and food.
我懂了
I see.
我连3天都没有坚持下来
I didn't even make it three days.
我想家了 于是打电话
叫我父母把我接回去了
I got homesick, called my parents to come and get me.
这是放武器的地方?
The weapons cache?
那么武器去哪了?
Well, where are the weapons?
很明显Bola kai没有拿走它们
Obviously, the Bola Kai don't have them.
我的族人肯定需要它们来反击
My people must have need them
to fight off the attack,
但是为什么他们没有成功呢?
but then why were they not successful?
Bola kai的武器跟这些肯定没法比
The Bola Kai's weapons
would have been no match against these.
- 那里
- 什么?
- Over there.
- What?
过了河有一个掩体
- There is a blind across the river.
掩体?
- A blind?
为了打猎用的 隐蔽性很好
For hunting.  It is well hidden.
可以用来做过夜的地方
It will provide shelter for the night.
我们得过那个?
We're going to cross that?
这是过河的最快的方法
It is the quickest way across.
你肯定是在开玩笑吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
这是我的族人架的
My people built it.
很安全的
It is quite safe.
哦...
I'm...
我也是这么觉得 只是...
I'm sure it is. It-it's just...
我...
Well, my...
我的脚踝 还有我内耳有病
my ankle, and I've also got this... inner ear thing.
我们叫它眩晕症 然后...
We call it vertigo, and...
上帝呀 你看看吧
God, look at it!
当不幸到达一定程度的时候
恐惧会消失 只留下求生的意念
There comes a point in adversity - leaving only the will to survive.
when fear disappears,
我知道 只是我不觉得
我和那有一点点接近
- I know, it's just, I don't think I'm even remotely close to that point.
好吧
Fine.
那就呆在这
Stay here then.
哦 好啦 等等
Oh, well, wait! I mean, I...
我是说...
I'm sure I could...
我确定我可以爬下山然后找一处...
I could climb down and find a...
水中的浅滩过河
Shallow spot in the river to cross.
那可能会多花一点时间... Teyla?
I mean, it might take me
a little longer but...
Teyla!
上帝呀
Oh, God...
开始了
Here we go.
这个非常的安全
It's perfectly safe...
非常安全
Perfectly safe.
有点晃
Wobbly...
很晃
Too wobbly...
快到了...
Almost there...
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们走
Come on.
也许你的人撑到了星门然后逃走了
Maybe your people managed to make it to the Gate and escape.
全部吗?
All of them?
我不知道 也许吧
Well, I don't know, maybe.
我们没有找到任何尸体 对吧?
I mean, we haven't found
any bodies, right?
据你说的 我觉得Bola kai
不会花时间来埋他们的食物的
From what you've said, take the time to bury their victims.
I doubt the Bola Kai would...
他们不会 因为他们吃完以后
通常也就不剩下什么了
No, they do not... because when they are done with their
victims, usually very little remains.
你说什么? 他们是吃人的吗?
What are you telling me,
they're cannibals?
Teyla?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事
- Yeah.
呆在这
- Stay here.
怎么了 Teyla?
What? Teyla!
Teyla!
那个死了
That's one's dead, but...
但是这个还活着
He's still alive.
我们不能收囚犯
We cannot afford to take prisoners.
我们可以...
Well, we could...
把他们绑起来 然后遗弃在丛林里
We could have tied
him up and left him in the woods.
这样别人会发现他
然后释放他重新加入追捕
Then the others would have found him
and released him to rejoin the hunt.
我知道这个很难接受 但是他们
的数量越少我们存活的几率就越大
I know it is difficult to accept, but the fewer of them,
the better our chances at survival.
他的手被绑起来了
His hands are tied.
他肯定是一个...
He must have been a...
一个囚犯
a prisoner.
他的腹部有一个刺伤
He's got a stab wound to his abdomen.
你能把我的医疗包递给我吗?
Will you get me my medical kit?
我们得把他留在这
We have to leave him.
你在说什么啊?
What are you talking about?
他是你的族人
He's one of your people.
他不是Athosian
He is not Athosian.
但是他的衣服...
But his... his clothes...
我从没见过他
I have never seen him before.
但明显他不是Bola kai
He's obviously not one of them,
如果我不缝合他的伤口
他会流血而死的
and if I don't suture his wound, he's going to bleed to death.
很快会有更多的Bola kai出现
More Bola Kai will be here very soon.
我知道 但这不会花很久的 好吗?
I know, but this won't take long, okay?
Please?
请你
Well...
我已经止住血了
I got the bleeding under control.
如果伤口不感染 他就会没事的
If the wound doesn't get infected,
he should be okay.
很快就要天黑了
It will be dark soon.
你和他呆在一起 我去找掩体
Stay here with him.
I will find the blind.
会很远吗?
- Is it far?
不远
- No.
找到了吗?
- Did you find it?
是的
- Yes.
他怎么样?
How is he?
还在昏迷状态 但是已经稳定了
Unconscious, but stable.
可以移动他吗?
Can he be moved?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
应该不行
He shouldn't be.
他的情形很危险 我不愿意..
His condition's precarious. I would hate to...
好吧 可以移动他
Yes, he can be moved.
从河里打来的水
- Water from the river.
谢谢你
- Thank you.
我已经在周围布了陷阱
I have laid traps around the perimeter.
如果有Bola kai接近 幸运的话
我们能在他找到我们之前听到他
If any Bola Kai come near, hopefully, we will hear them
before they discover us.
好的
Good.
你的脚踝怎么样了?
How's your ankle?
肿得不是很厉害
The swelling's not too bad...
多亏了止痛药 疼痛也好多了
And the pain's eased up,
thanks to the painkillers.
如果你想睡觉 我可以...
If you wish to sleep, I can...
什么?
What?
那是什么?
What is that?
晚餐
Dinner.
他们被我们的体热吸引
They are attracted
to the warmth of our bodies.
味道不太好 但是可以维持生命
The taste leaves much to be desired,
but it will sustain you.
不用了 谢谢 我不饿
No, thanks, I'm not hungry.
你应该吃一点
You should eat.
这是我对求生最讨厌的一部分
This was my least
favorite part of survivor.
他清醒过来了
He's regaining consciousness.
没事的
It's okay.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
你是谁?
Who are you?
Nabel Golan...Genii
Nabel Golan... of the Genii.
Genii?
The Genii?
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我被被安插进Athosian中间...
I was planted
to work inside the Athosian community...
收集情报
To gather intel.
他们发生了什么事?
What happened to them?
死了
Dead.
全部都死了
All of them.
谁杀了他们?
Who killed my people?
Wraith
Wraith.
洗劫了整个定居点
A culling. Entire settlement.
不是Bola kai?
Not the Bola Kai?
Bola kai把他们的事告诉了Wraith
Bola Kai were the ones
who told the Wraith about them.
Bola kai是Wraith崇拜者?
The Bola Kai are Wraith worshipers?
我逃过了攻击但是没法到达星门
I was able to... escape during the attack, but I was cut off from the Gate.
Bola kai在把守
Bola Kai were guarding it.
他们抓住了我
They captured me.
我从没见过你
I have never seen you before.
你在我的族人间生活了多久了?
How long have you lived among my people?
我是几天之前才到的
I only arrived a few days ago.
你们从哪来?
Where are you from?
她是我从另一个星球来的朋友
She is a friend of mine
from another world.
你的一起 看上去像是古人的
Your equipment, it looks ancestral.
我们在旅行途中发现的
We discovered it in our travels.
我们离开了一段时间去做交易
We have been away
for some time, trading.
交易?
Trading?
和谁交易?
With who?
如果你还在刺探情报
If you are still seeking intel,
你就是在浪费你仅剩的一点力气了
then you are wasting
what few breaths you have remaining.
说"谢谢你们救了我"
So say, "thank you for saving me",
然后我们的谈话就此结束
and be done with this discussion.
谢谢...
Thank you...
你们救了我
for saving me.
你一个晚上都没睡
You have not slept all night.
有人在追杀我们 附近还有
会遁地的动物 我怎么睡得着?
With people trying to kill us and... creatures crawling around
under the ground?
更不用说我是多么饿
Not to mention I'm starving.
不是这种饿
Not that starving.
这个能给你力量
- It will give you strength.
这个会使我呕吐
- It'll make me puke.
你不相信你有能力吃下它
所以你不吃
You do not believe and so you do not.
you are capable of eating it,
不 我认为它很恶心 所以才不吃
No, I think it's disgusting, and so I do not.
我有一个朋友和你很像
害怕挑战自己
I have a friend like you, afraid to challenge himself.
我不是害怕挑战
I'm not afraid of challenges.
我报名做了一个
跨星系探险队的首席医生
I signed up to be chief of medicine on an expedition
in a whole other galaxy.
这是最具有挑战性的事了
但是吃这么粗劣的食物?
That's about as challenging as it gets, but eating gross food?
对不起 我绝对是要区别对待的
Sorry, but that's where I draw the line.
很好
Fair enough.
看见了
See?
没有吐哦
No puking.
嗯
Yet.
那么你的这个朋友...
So this... friend of yours...
是你队里的成员吗?
One of your team members?
也许是某个保守的天体物理学家?
A certain uptight astrophysicist maybe?
不是
No.
是一个Athosian
Athosian.
他叫Kanan
His name is Kanan.
一个天生的领袖
但是被天生的过虑所累
A natural leader,
but he is unaware of it,
自己不觉得(自己是个领袖)
burdened by an overly cautious nature.
他不仅仅是一个朋友吧?
He's more than a friend, isn't he?
他就是你要见的人
He's the one you were coming to see.
那个"激情约会"
The hot date.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这不关我的事
It's none of my business.
我应该学者闭嘴的
I should just learn to shut up.
我们从小就认识
We have known each other
since childhood,
但是最近才发展到超越友谊的程度
but only recently kindled
more than a friendship.
我还没有告诉任何人呢
I have not told anyone yet.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我们需要更多的水
We need more water.
我们得走了
We have to leave.
发生了什么?
- What happened?
你可以走路吗?
- Can you walk?
我认为他站都站不起来
I don't even think he can stand.
很快 很多Bola kai就会到达这里
Very soon, many more
Bola Kai will be here.
没事的
It's all right.
我可以走
I can walk.
Mr. Freeze 不对 是King Tut
(以下五人皆是蝙蝠侠电视剧中人物)
Mr. Freeze, no, King Tut.
两个都错了
Otto Breminger演的是Mr. Freeze
Wrong on both.
Otto Preminger was Mr. Freeze.
Victor Buono是King Tut
Victor Buono was King Tut.
Vincent Price是Egghead
- Vincent Price was Egghead.
Egghead 没错
- Egghead, right.
那好 Cliff Robertson是?
Okay, so, Cliff Robertson?
我我知道这个 他演牛仔的对吧?
Oh, I know this one.
Played the cowboy, right?
嘿
Hey.
Teyla和Keller回来了吗?
Teyla and Keller get back?
我还没有听到他们的消息呢
- I haven't heard from them yet.
他们迟到了
- They're late.
这听上去不像Teyla的作风
- That doesn't sound like Teyla.
一点也不像
- No, it doesn't.
她昨晚吃了个大餐
Well, she had that big feast last night.
也许她玩过头了 需要多睡点觉
Maybe she did too much celebrating,
and needs to sleep it off.
嗯 这听上去很像Teyla
Yeah, that sounds like Teyla.
我们呼叫她一下
Let's give her a call.
Shame
- Shame.
- 什么东西?
- Cliff Robertson
- What is? Cliff Robertson.
他扮演的那个反派 Shame
The villain he played, Shame.
很好 Shelley Winters
Very good. Shelley Winters.
你们两个在说什么啊?
What the hell are you talking about?
我得休息一下
I need to rest.
他在拖累我们
而且使你的脚伤更严重了
He is slowing us down, and he is making
your ankle injury worse.
如果我们把他丢在这
Bola kai会抓住他的
Well, if we leave him behind,
the Bola Kai are going to capture him.
如果继续这样 我们都会被抓住的
If we continue this way,
we will all be captured.
我承认我对某些事不太在行
Look, I'm the first to admit I'm not very good at certain things.
我不会运动 我不能烧饭
你都不会愿意听我弹钢琴
I'm not athletic, I can't cook, and you don't even want to hear me
try to play the piano,
但是我想我很会看人
but I do think I'm a pretty good
judge of character,
我知道你绝对不会为了就自己
and I know that you would never sacrifice an innocent man,
牺牲一个无辜的人
即使他是一个陌生人
not even if he was a complete stranger, to save yourself,
也就是说你提出这个意见
完全是为了我
which means the only reason you would
even suggest it would be because of me.
我带你来的
I brought you here.
这是我的责任
This is my responsibility.
如果你有什么不测...
If anything should happen to you...
我自己报名的 对吧?
I signed up for this, all right?
全部的这些事
All of it.
我也许本来没有
任何概念我会面对什么
I may not have had any idea
what I was getting into,
但是这不会使我
区别于Atlantis上的任何人
but... that makes me no different
from anybody else on Atlantis.
我很高兴你这么想
- I'm glad you feel that way...
我知道...
- Oh, yeah, I know, I know.
但在事情结束之前
我要尽量鼓足勇气
Before this is all over, I'm gonna have
to find all the courage I can muster.
事实上
Actually...
你现在就要
You're going to need
to find it right now.
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
Teyla!
Teyla Atlantis呼叫 收到吗?
Teyla? This is Atlantis, do you read?
Teyla 我是Sheppard 回话
Teyla, this is Sheppard, come in.
她绝不会关掉对讲机的
She wouldn't turn off her radio.
她不会的
No, she wouldn't.
呼叫Athosian定居点的任何人
这是John Sheppard中校
Calling anyone this is Lieutenant Colonel
in the Athosian settlement, John Sheppard.
收到吗?
Do you copy?
Teyla 这是Sheppard 请回话...
Teyla, this is Sheppard,
please respond...
他们要对我们怎么样?
What are they going to do to us?
我们会试着获取信息
They will try to extricate information.
我们什么都不能说
We must tell them nothing.
Keller医生 Atlantis里的
每一个人都有生命危险
Dr. Keller, the lives of everyone
in Atlantis are at stake.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你从哪来?
Where are you from?
什么?
What?
你的家在那?
Your home?
Chippewa Falls 威斯康星州
Chippewa Falls, Wisconsin.
一个小镇
A little town.
你有家人吗?
Do you have any family?
只有我爸爸了
Just my dad.
我妈妈几年前死了
My mom died a few years back.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你一定很想他
You must miss him.
我是他仅剩的东西了
I'm all he's got left.
那么你必须要尽可能去求生
去返回家园
Then you must do to return home.
everything you can to survive,
你必须...
You must...
你会活下来的
You will survive.
你会活着回家的 你听懂了嘛?
You will return home.
Do you understand?
你们是谁?
Who are you?
我是Athosian
I am Athosian.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我不管你相信什么
I do not care what you believe.
你越不讲话 就会越惨
The longer you are silent,
the worse it will be for you.
我告诉过你
I told you.
我们是Athosian 你会为你对
我的人民所做的一切付出代价
We are Athosian, and you will suffer for what
you have done to our people.
我们做的一切?
What we've done?
你谋杀了他们 一整个村庄
You murdered them, an entire village.
我们到的时候那个村庄已经没人了
That village was deserted
when we arrived.
没人了是因为那里被
你们带来的Wraith洗劫了
Deserted because Wraith who were brought here by you.
it was culled by the Wraith,
你知道我们是谁吗?
Do you know who we are?
你们是Bola kai
You are Bola Kai.
那你知道我们像
其他人一样都被Wraith捕杀
Then you know we are hunted
by the Wraith like everyone else.
除非你们是Wraith崇拜者
Unless you are Wraith worshipers.
把她带出去
Get her out of here!
我会饶了她一命
如果你告诉我你是谁
I'm willing to spare her life if you tell me who you are.
你有告诉他们什么吗?
Did you tell them anything?
他们说他们会杀了你的
They said they would kill you.
你和他们说了Atlantis的事?
You told them about Atlantis?
没有
No.
我...
I...
我给了他们一个无人的星球的地址
I gave them a Gate address,
只是调虎离山 就像你说的
为我们赢得一些时间
an uninhabited planet, buy us more time, like you said.
just to throw them off,
我不觉得他们是Wraith崇拜者
I don't think they're Wraith worshipers.
那个人被你指控帮助Wraith
的时候真的很惊讶
That guy in there, he seemed surprised when you accused him
of working with the Wraith.
如果这是实情 他为什么会否认?
Why would he deny it if it was true?
我认为他承认以后就可以
更好地威胁我们讲出实情
I would think that would provide to get us to talk.
an even more effective threat
那难道他们正好就在
定居点刚被洗劫以后来到了这里?
So they just happened to arrive here moments after the settlement was culled?
我觉得这太巧合了
I find that a coincidence.
有东西刚从大门里通过
是一种飞船
Something just came through the portal,
a flying ship of some kind, but
但是在我们能反应之前就消失了
it disappeared before
we could do anything.
你们两个 看住他们
You two, watch them.
剩下的人 拿上武器跟我来
The rest of you,
get your weapons and come with me!
我们不用等多久了
Not much longer.
把守星门的人看上去
肯定不是Athosian
Those guys guarding the Gates
certainly don't look Athosian.
他们是Bola kai
- They're Bola Kai.
- 什么人?
- 是一个武士部落
- What? It a warrior tribe. Ruthless.
很残忍 喜欢挑起战争
They like picking fights,
尤其是对和平的部落
especially with tribes who are peaceful.
太好了 正是我们需要的
另一帮坏蛋
Great, just what we need,
another bad guy.
别担心
Don't worry.
他们很原始 我们可以搞定他们的
They're primitive.
We can handle them.
定义一下"原始"
Define primitive.
木棍和弓箭
- Clubs and arrows.
嘿 弓箭是可以伤人的
- Hey, arrows can hurt.
只有在你笨到
可以让屁股中箭的时候
Only if you're stupid enough
to get hit in the ass with one.
生命信号?
- Life signs?
到处都是 绝大多数在森林里
- All over the place. Mostly in the woods.
这里很难看得清楚
It's hard to get a visual from up here.
好吧 我们得徒步行进
All right, we'll have to go
on foot then.
带上装备 伙计们
Gear up, boys.
如果这些家伙想要战斗
就好好地和他们干一架
If these guys want a fight, happy to give it to 'em.
John?
Nabel...
后退
Move back.
你的枪是从哪来的?
Where did you get the gun?
Athosian不是唯一会藏武器的民族
The Athosians were not the only ones
with a hidden cache of weapons.
Bola kai在我到达我
放武器的地方之前把我抓住了
The Bola Kai captured me
before I could get to mine.
我们得快点走
We need to get moving.
他们肯定听到了枪声
They no doubt heard the gunfire.
他们追来了吗?
They coming?
看上去没有
It does not appear so.
我觉得可以安全的休息了
I believe it is safe to rest.
谢谢你来救我们
Thank you for coming for us.
你们救了我
You saved my life.
我觉得我应该还你们人情
I figured I'd return the favor.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
我还不能死呢
Well, I can't die yet.
我有太多的问题需要求解
I have far too many questions
I need answers to first.
我们可以从你告诉我
Atlantis的星门地址开始
We can start with you giving me
the Gate address to Atlantis.
我检测到生命信号
这边 这边 这边 还有这边
I've got lifesigns, there, there, there, and there.
这真是缩小范围了
- That really narrows it down.
这边走
- That way.
真的? 为什么?
Really? Why?
没有理由
No reason.
对我来说足够了
Good enough for me.
我们走
Let's go.
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
告诉我地址 我就放你们走
Just give me the address
and I'll let you go.
我保证
I promise.
看来你的伤没有我想象的那么严重
I see you're not
as badly wounded as I thought.
哦 伤很严重
Oh, it's bad.
只是我很能忍受疼痛
I just have a high tolerance for pain.
告诉我地址 然后我就让你们走
The address, and I'll let you go, both of you.
你在骗人
You're lying.
你不是Genii 对吧?
You're not Genii, are you?
我们和他们有共识
We have an understanding with them.
他们不会依靠这种手段来联系我们
They wouldn't need to resort
to these tactics in order to contact us.
好吧 那一部分不是真的
但我确实被Bola kai抓住了
All right, so that part wasn't true, but I was captured by the Bola Kai.
你是Wraith崇拜者
You're the Wraith worshiper.
是你造成了那些Athosian的死
You're the one responsible
for the death of the Athosians.
除非...我在这个上面撒谎了
Unless I lied about that as well.
你什么意思? 他们没有死?
What do you mean, they're not dead?
告诉我地址 然后我会
很乐意地告诉你一切
Give me the Gate address, and I'll gladly tell you everything.
别动
- Don't move.
解开我
- Untie me.
让开
- Get out of the way.
把枪给我
- Give me the gun.
我会开枪的
I'll shoot you.
你不会的
No, you won't.
你的本性不是这样的
You don't have it in you.
你是一个医生 一个治疗者
You're a doctor, a healer...
不是一个杀手
Not a killer.
你说的没错 我是一个治疗者
You're right, I am a healer,
但是首先我得有东西治
but first I need something to heal.
我的人怎么了?
What happened to my people?
他们怎么了?
What happened to them?
你没事吧?
- You okay?
没事
- Yeah.
发生了什么?
What happened?
我的人 他们不见了
My people, they are gone.
你说什么? 都不见了? 怎么回事?
What are you talking about?
All of them? What happened?
Nabel!
他去哪了?
- Where did he go?
我没看见
- I didn't see.
你们在说谁啊?
Who are you talking about?
是箭!
Not arrows!
我们得离开了!
We need to move!
快点 我们走!
Come on, let's go! Well...
你感觉怎么样?
How you feeling?
我没事
I am fine.
Keller医生坚持让我卧床
Dr. Keller insists I remain in bed.
她害怕我有脑震荡
She fears I have a concussion.
你应该听她的
Well, you should listen to her.
我们刚从New Athos回来
We just got back from New Athos.
Bola kai都走了
The Bola Kai are all gone.
我们肯定把他们吓怕了
Must have scared them off.
Rodney已经带人去搜集
你的族人的线索
Rodney's got teams going out there to collect clues about
what happened to your people.
你们有找到Nabel 吗?
Did you find Nabel?
搜遍了整个星球 没有生命信号
Searched the entire planet,
no life signs.
他肯定是从星门逃走了
He must have escaped through the Gate.
或者更有可能的是 他暴尸荒野了
Or, more likely,
he's lying dead somewhere.
他知道我的族人发生了什么
He knows what happened to my people.
我会找到他们的
I will find them.
我知道你会的 而且我们会帮助你
I know you will,
and we're going to help you,
但是你现在得休息 恢复体力
but you've got to rest
and get your strength back.
不管这是谁做的 他都要复出代价
Whoever did this will pay.
我保证
I will make certain of it.
你感觉怎么样 医生
Hey, Doc, how you feeling?
只是扭伤 我会没事的
Oh, it's just a sprain. I'll be fine.
为什么你可以恢复工作
但是我不行?
Why is it that you are allowed
to resume working, and I am not?
因为我没参与那么多打斗
Because I didn't take
half the beating you did.
我经历过更糟糕的情况
- I have suffered worse.
我相信你 但是你在我的地盘上
- Yeah, well, I believe you, but you're on my turf now,
你就得听我的
so you have to listen to me.
我晚些再来看你
I'll check in on you later.
那么...
So...
我得到许可回家休几天假
(R&R=美国军队每年5天之假期)
I got permission to go home
for a few days of R&R.
上帝保佑那个跨星系星门桥能用
God bless that
intergalactic gate bridge, huh?
不管怎么样
Anyway...
我得去看看我爸爸
I get to see my dad...
为这个我得谢谢你
And I have you to thank for that.
我在这要住多久?
How long must I stay here?
再有一两天吧
About another day or so.
我告诉过你了 我没事
I told you, I feel fine.
我没有脑震荡
I do not have a concussion.
没错
You're right.
你没有
You don't.
Teyla 我看过你的检测结果了
Teyla, I've looked over
your test results.
我有件事要和你谈谈...
There's something we need to talk about.